MEGAN GILPIN

3692 Broadway #43, NY, NY 10031 / **T**: (620) 481-1538 /

E: megangilpin@gmail.com

CONNECT



in linkedin.com/in/megan-gilpin



github.com/megangilpin

SKILLS

// PROFESSIONAL

- Critical Thinking
- Communication
- Project Management
- Leadership
- Presentation

// TECHNICAL

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- MySQL, MongoDB
- node.js, Express.js
- ¡Query, Bootstrap
- Git, Heroku
- Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- Adobe XD
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator

EDUCATION

COLUMBIA ENGINEERING -FULL-STACK BOOT CAMP

Columbia University - 2019

BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS / FASHION DESIGN

The Illinois Institute of Art-Chicago - 2009

SUMMER INTENSIVE STUDY / FASHION DESIGN

Parsons, The New School for Design - Summer 2006

PROFILE

Versatile full stack engineer at the intersection of functionality and design with 10 years of experience as a menswear designer developing creative consumer-focused products and the proven ability to oversee the strategy and growth of product categories. An underlying passion for innovation has driven the pursuit of full stack web development through the Columbia Engineering Boot camp.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

COLUMBIA ENGINEERING - CODING BOOT CAMP

Full Stack Developer | New York, NY April 2019 - Present

- Created scalable web apps, APIs, and services with HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, MySQL, and Mongo DB.
- Collaborated with peers to create real-world projects in a professional environment.
- Developed MERN applications using knowledge of data structures and algorithms
- Established full understanding of responsive web design through CSS, Bootstrap, and React.js

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DESIGNER - OUTERWEAR / BOTTOMS / DENIM

Original Penguin | New York, NY 2014 - Present

- · Oversee concept, design, and production of the global assortment of outerwear, bottoms, and denim; 450 skus per year for retail, DTC, and wholesale stores in over 30 countries.
- Maximized outerwear sourcing and design to improve margin by 10% within first year; consecutively achieved new maximum target margin per sku in all following years.
- Implemented bottom category relaunch, resulting in 83% growth in bottoms share of the total sales mix.
- Interpret global trend research to create a quarterly report of seasonal and category initiatives.
- Present concepts and designs to internal teams, including an annual global sales launch for an audience of over 200 people.
- Coordinate with cross-functional teams to approve all development and bulk production to ensure quality and aesthetic meets brand standards and calendars.

ASSOCIATE DESIGNER-OUTERWEAR / SUIT SEPARATES

Kenneth Cole | New York, NY 2011-2014

- Created designs and developed fabrics and trims for Kenneth Cole, Reaction, and Outlet lines.
- Assisted in growing Reaction business from 150 Macy's doors to Macy's all doors.
- Managed CAD designer to ensure optimal productivity.
- Partnered with cross-functional teams to interpret selling results, sku plans, and design calendar to create product within given price ranges and time frames.
- · Communicated with overseas agents in over 5 countries throughout all stages of development and production.

FREELANCE DESIGNER-KNITS/DENIM/OUTERWEAR/SUIT SEP.

Kenneth Cole | New York, NY 2009-2011

- Built and maintained technical packages sent to overseas agents.
- Reviewed and sent out comments for fabric, trim, and fittings from development to production.
- Researched and interpreted trends to create brand right trend presentations for Kenneth Cole and Reaction lines.